marketingtipsmail.com 2016-06-01

# Privacy - PaidViewpoint

**Policy Effective Date:** March 2011  
**Last Revised:** April 7th, 2015  
This page discloses the privacy policy and practices of the PaidViewPoint.com website ("PV"), a website owned and operated by Umongous, Inc ("Umongous"), a Delaware Corporation. Umongous also owns and operates AYTM.com, a market research website that has Clients (Umongous Clients or Clients) who utilize data obtained from PV as described below. 

Umongous in is the market research and opinion research business. Umongous operates PV for the purpose of gaining anonymous opinions, such as your opinions, in order to help its Clients gain a better understanding of their business, marketing, product development and strategic opportunities. Umongous and some of its Clients also collect your anonymous opinions for the purposes of research related to understanding sociological, political and educational issues. The Clients of Umongous use this information in an aggregated fashion and do not receive from Umongous your identity or the individual identities of other PV panel members. It is against Umongous policy and market research terms of service ("MR-TOS") for one of its clients' to seek to determine the individual identity of any PV panel member. 

Umongous has been awarded TRUSTe's Privacy Seal signifying that this privacy policy and practices have been reviewed by TRUSTe for compliance with [TRUSTe's program requirements](http://www.truste.com/privacy-program-requirements/) including transparency, accountability and choice regarding the collection and use of your personal information. The TRUSTe program does not cover information that may be collected through downloadable software. The TRUSTe program covers only information that is collected through this Web site, [http://www.paidviewpoint.com](http://www.paidviewpoint.com/). TRUSTe's mission, as an independent third party, is to accelerate online trust among consumers and organizations globally through its leading privacy Trustmark and innovative trust solutions. If you have questions or complaints regarding our privacy policy or practices on PV, please contact us at privacy [at] paidviewpoint [dot] com, or you can also write to us at: Umongous, Inc c/o AYTM PO Box 1741 Absecon, NJ 08201. 

If you are not satisfied with our response you can contact [TRUSTe here](https://feedback-form.truste.com/watchdog/request). 

PV processes personal information on our servers in the United States of America. Your Personal Information may be transferred to, and used by, entities located outside of your state, province, country or other governmental jurisdiction where the privacy laws may not be as protective as those in your jurisdiction. Such export is a requirement of providing your information to PV, and you hereby consent to such export in all respects. 

The company complies with the U.S.-E.U. Safe Harbor Framework and the U.S.-Swiss Safe Harbor Framework as set forth by the U.S. Department of Commerce regarding the collection, use, and retention of personal information from European Union member countries and Switzerland. The Umongous, Inc. has certified that it adheres to the Safe Harbor Privacy Principles of notice, choice, onward transfer, security, data integrity, access, and enforcement. To learn more about the Safe Harbor program, and to view the Umongous, Inc.’s certification, please visit <http://www.export.gov/safeharbor>. 

## Our Privacy Pledge:

### When you participate at PV as a member, your privacy is protected.

You will notice when you register at PV that we do not ask for your full name. We ask for a user name for the purpose of addressing you in emails and displaying your wins to our community on our home page and past winner's pages. You are free to supply a pseudonym on PV. We are not interested in your real name. We also do not ask for your precise address. Depending on your country of residence, you may need to supply your phone number in order to validate your account. In the US, we ask for your state, county and zip code. In other countries we may as for similar geographic and postal information, but not your precise address. We ask for your email address at registration. We will not rent, sell or share your email address with anyone without your expressed permission, except in the rare instances required by law such as to comply with a subpoena, or similar legal process and when we believe in good faith that disclosure is necessary to protect our rights, protect your safety or the safety of others, investigate fraud, or respond to a government request. 

You are able, at your option, to upload an avatar into your account. This is entirely voluntary. The avatar may be your true likeness or photo at your sole discretion. If you choose to upload an avatar, PV may from time to time display your avatar on publicly viewable portions of the website and label the avatar with your first name, first initial of your last name supplied at registration, and account winnings or cash out. Your avatar may be overlaid on a map and show your approximate registered location. Umongous will not share your avatar with Umongous Clients or associate it with any survey answers. Should you decline to upload an avatar, PV may on occasion display a stock avatar image along with your first name, first initial of last name and account winnings or cash out. 

If you use a social media login, such as Facebook, your social media profile photo and name will be shared with us through the relevant API. In those cases, PV will display your social media profile photo as your avatar on PV. Your true name, obtained from the API will also be displayed on your profile page within PV. Your registration demographics, such as your relationship status, household income, employment status, etc., will not be displayed on your PV profile page for others to see nor shared in a personally identifiable fashion with any third party at any time, with the exception of PV employees who may be required to service your account. Your precise answers to survey questions and traits questions will not be displayed on your PV profile page nor shared in a personally identifiable fashion, with any third party at any time with the exception of PV employees who may be required to service your account. 

We do share your anonymous demographics, which you supply during registration or periodically update, with our Clients, along with your survey answers. Although our Clients are not interested in your personal identity, theoretically (in unusual circumstances), there could be cases where our Clients might be able to determine your personal identity. An example would be if you live in a zip code with a very small population and your demographics are unique for that zip code. In practice, we are unaware of any of our Clients making this effort. Such an effort by Umongous Clients is against our policy and MR-TOS. Because our Umongous survey system is self-service, it is possible that one of our Clients could potentially violate our policies and MR-TOS and deploy a survey into PV that requests personally identifiable information ("PII"). We urge you not to answer any question in a market research survey that requests PII such as your real name, address, phone number, social security number or email address. If you see such a violation on PV, please report this violation to notification [at] paidviewpoint [dot] com. 

We will share your personal information with third parties only in the ways that are described in this privacy policy. Umongous will never try to sell you anything. We will never share, rent, sell or provide your email address to anyone else who might want to sell you anything. We are not in the lead generation business and it is against our MR-TOS for Umongous Clients to use our system and attempt to access you through PV for that purpose. 

We may provide your personal information to companies that provide services to help us with our business activities such as delivering your incentive, shipping materials and tools, needed for conducting research, or offering customer service. These companies are authorized to use your personal information only as necessary to provide these services to us. 

Your individual responses to surveys will also be kept confidential and will never be linked to your personal identifying information WITH THE EXCEPTION THAT Umongous does supply the demographics provided by you at registration and kept updated by you in your profile including state, county, zip code and inferred city or town. This information is supplied to Umongous Clients along with your survey answers so that they can make determinations about the opinions of people who generically are similar to you. 

If you ever see a survey that you do not wish to answer, exit the current session in your browser and come back PV at a later time. It will be removed from your account due to completion of the number of responses ordered by the Umongous Client, and no longer appear when you log in to PV. Do not answer any survey in which you do not wish to participate. 

Many of the surveys you will encounter while participating at PV exist for the purpose of identifying certain psychographic characteristics such as interests, activities, personal opinions and possessions. Umongous uses this information to direct certain surveys by Umongous Clients to you. For example, you might be asked if you own a pickup truck because a Umongous Client either does or doesn't wish to survey people who own pickup trucks. 

Many questions asked in non-market-research surveys shown to you at PV are used by Umongous to make a determination about whether you are carefully reading questions and providing deliberate, consistent and candid answers. Your answers to these questions are used to determine whether Umongous will ask you to complete market research surveys. The magnitude of your opportunity to win monetary compensation on PV is largely predicated upon your level of activity on PV AND our determination of whether you are reading questions carefully and providing deliberate, consistent, candid answers. We use our proprietary algorithm "TraitScore" to make that determination. Umongous is always seeking to provide the highest quality service to its Clients and looks to you to be candid and truthful with your opinions. 

### Other information Collected by PV During Your Visits

PV automatically collects information and records in its database log files to help administer the site and aid in technical problem solving. Examples of log file information collected include IP address, time a page was viewed, your browser type, URL parameters, and information from cookies that were set by PV at the time of the visit. IP addresses are correlated with your declared location such as zip code. Use of proxy servers to mask your location is a violation of PV terms of service ("TOS"). It is important for PV to prevent users from creating and operating multiple accounts. Log file information is never linked to personal identifying information other than the information provided in your account profile. 

### Other Activities/Games on PV

As a member of PV you may optionally elect to participate in PredictionMatch and other PV contests. In order to participate you may be required to login to PV using your Facebook account. This will result in your Facebook profile photo being used as your avatar within PV, in the "top score" charts and on your profile page unless you provided a separate avatar within your PV account. That profile page is viewable by other members of PV. Your name as registered at Facebook may also appear on your profile page and be viewable by others. Once you have activated contests in your account, should you later decide to opt out, you must log in to your account and choose "opt out" within your profile settings. You may also choose to notify us by contacting PV at support [at] paidviewpoint [dot] com. 

Your demographics and specific answers to questions in surveys or PV contests will not be shared with anyone in a manner that can be linked to your personal identity. For instance, your household income that you supplied at registration will not be shared with anyone in a manner that can be personally linked to you. Your Facebook login credentials are never received nor stored on PV servers. Other members of PV can see your success in PV contests. 

### Links to Other Web Sites

Our Site includes links to other Web sites whose privacy practices may differ from those of Umongous. If you submit personal information to any of those sites, your information is governed by their privacy statements. We encourage you to carefully read the privacy statement of any Web site you visit. 

We may learn your name on certain other occasions, but we do not then store it within PV databases or use it for any other purpose than to resolve a customer support issue initiated by you. For instance, if you send us an email, your name may be revealed to us in your email address, or because you have used your name in your email. We do not encourage you to publicly reveal your name even though no third parties will be able to see your registration demographics or other personal information. When we send you money by PayPal.com, your name may be revealed to us in our Paypal account but we will not transfer your name from there to the PV database. 

### Customer Testimonials/Comments/Reviews/User Feedback

We post customer testimonials/comments/reviews on Web sites owned or controlled by Umongous, which may contain PII. We do obtain the customer's consent via email to post their name along with their testimonial prior to posting the testimonial. If you wish to update or delete your testimonial, you can contact us at privacy [at] paidviewpoint [dot] com. 

### Inviting Friends to Join PV

When you invite a friend to subscribe or become a member of PV using the tools provided to you by PV, a code will be provided to them to become linked to you in our PV database ("Linked"). Once Linked to the friend that you referred (the "Referral"), you will become eligible to potentially receive a recruiting bonus. The username of your invited friend may be shown to you in your profile. Your friend may contact us at privacy [at] paidviewpoint [dot] com to request that we remove this information from our database. 

Our Web site includes Social Media Features, such as the Facebook Like button and Widgets, such as the Share this button or interactive mini-programs that run on our site. These Features may collect your IP address, which page you are visiting on our site, and may set a cookie to enable the Feature to function properly. Social Media Features and Widgets are either hosted by a third party or hosted directly on our Site. Your interactions with these Features are governed by the privacy policy of the company providing it. 

### Facebook Connect or Open ID

You can log in to our site using sign-in services such as Facebook Connect or an Open ID provider. These services will authenticate your identity and provide you the option to share certain personal information with us such as your name and email address to pre-populate our sign up form. Services like Facebook Connect give you the option to post information about your activities on this Web site to your profile page to share with others within your network. 

### Data Security

PV has industry standard security measures in place to protect the loss, misuse, and alteration of the information under our control. These procedures are in place to secure PV member email addresses, anonymous demographics, psychographics and survey answers. PV members may access their demographics within their profile page for the purposes of verifying and updating. Under no circumstance can one member view the demographics of another member. As with any Internet endeavor, absolute security of information transmitted through channels (communication networks, hardware, software) not directly operated or controlled by us cannot be guaranteed. No method of transmission over the Internet, or method of electronic storage, is 100% secure, however. Therefore, we cannot guarantee its absolute security. 

In the event PV and/or Umongous or its affiliates enters into a merger, acquisition, sale or other transaction pursuant to which PV, or any portion of Umongous assets is acquired by a third party or an affiliate of Umongous, or is subject to bankruptcy, your personal information may be disclosed to the third party or affiliate both before and after the transaction, for the sole purpose of facilitating the transfer of your account and effecting that transaction. In the event a transaction is consummated, you will be notified of the transaction via email and/or through a notice on our website, and custody of your personal information will be transferred subject to all the terms and restrictions in this privacy policy. In the event the transaction is not consummated, PV and Umongous will require the third party or affiliate not to use or disclose your personal information in any manner whatsoever and to completely erase the same. 

As is the case with any information you provide to any business operating in the United States, information provided to PV is subject to disclosure pursuant to judicial or other government subpoenas, warrants, or orders. 

### Policies on Correcting and Updating Personal Information

PV relies on its members themselves to provide any updates to demographic information. To change your personal information on PV, please log into your PV account and click on the profile link on the top right hand corner of the page. Then choose "settings" from the menu provided. If you wish to change your demographic information, please click on the profile link at the top right-hand corner of the webpage and choose the "my demographics" link. If you wish to contact us for assistance, please email us at support [at] paidviewpoint [dot] com. 

## Opt Out Policy:

### You Can Decide at Any Time to End Participation

You can decline to respond to any survey by either selecting the "skip" button if available for non-market-research surveys or, if not available by logging out of a session when faced with a market research survey and then logging back in at a later time when it is no longer being shown to you. If you desire to cancel your membership in PV, please use the "Close account" button on the bottom of "Settings" page or contact us at support [at] paidviewpoint [dot] com. We will promptly cancel your account and delete your information from our database and send you a confirmation email. We respect your decision to decline participation and will not make any attempt to dissuade you. 

## Use of Cookies and tracking technology:

### How We Use Cookies & Other Technologies on Our Website

Technologies such as: cookies, beacons, tags and scripts are used by Umongous and our research, technology, and marketing partners, affiliates, analytics, service, incentive deliver providers, etc.. These technologies are used in analyzing trends, administering the site, tracking users’ movements around the site and to gather demographic information about our user base as a whole. We may receive reports based on the use of these technologies by these companies on an individual as well as aggregated basis. 

We use cookies to store user credential automatically, to remember users’ settings and protect unauthorized access.. Users can control the use of cookies at the individual browser level. If you reject cookies, you may still use our site, but your ability to use some features or areas of our site may be limited. 

We use Local Storage Objects (LSOs) such as HTML5 to enforce the rules, store content information and preferences etc. 

Various browsers may offer their own management tools for removing HTML5 LSOs. 

### PV May Use Digital Fingerprinting

Digital fingerprinting is a technology used to place a unique identifier on a device such as a computer or smartphone. PV digital fingerprinting will never change the functionality of a device, collect personal information, or affect the operating system or its settings in any way. It will never log keystrokes or record activities. It will never interfere with or take control of the device. It will never send any information to the PV servers other than the device ID. It will never act as malware, adware, a virus or a Trojan. Its sole purpose is to match the device ID to the PV accounts logged into from the device. It is used to ensure the integrity of the market research results obtained on PV. It is also used to help prevent violations of the one account per PV member rule. PV uses commercially reasonable efforts to ensure that this technology is safe, secure and does not cause undue privacy or data security risks. PV will use and distribute this technology in an ethical manner in accordance with the PV privacy policy and all applicable laws. 

## Children's Privacy

The site is intended for adults in the United States. We do not intentionally or knowingly collect personally identifiable information from children under the age of 13 and we request that individuals under the age of 13 not submit any personal information on the site. If we become aware that a child under the age of 13 has created an account at PV, we will promptly close that account and delete any submitted information. 

## How and When PV May Contact You

### Uses of Information

When you register for an account on PV, you will be required to call us with your landline or cell phone or send us an SMS to provide PV with a secret validation code presented to you by PV. As a result of this process, we will learn your phone number. We populate your phone number into your account where you can see it and change it in the future. This validation procedure is designed to add security to your account and to limit PV members from creating multiple accounts. The same process must be repeated each time you cash out. We do use a third party application [Twilio](http://www.twilio.com/) to receive the confirmation codes from your phone and identify your phone number to our database. Please refer to the [Twilio Privacy Policy](http://www.twilio.com/legal/privacy) for further details. At no other time does PV share your phone number with any third party or display it to others on the PV website. 

### Invitations

PV may send you an email from time to time to invite you to take a survey. You may opt-out from receiving PV emails by selecting the opt-out link in the email or on the "Settings" page. 

### Reminder Emails

PV may send you an email to remind you that you can return to the site to begin answering surveys. These reminder emails are sent at your specific request based upon a setting that you have made in your account. If you do not request another reminder be sent to you next time, then none will be sent. To change these settings on PV, please log into your account and click on the profile link in the top right-hand corner, then click on the settings tab where you can turn off these notifications. 

### Service-related Announcements

From time-to-time we may send you service-related transactional emails. You may opt-out from receiving these emails by selecting the opt-out link in the email. 

### Promotional Emails

Occasionally we may send you a promotional email concerning some feature, service or promotion directly related to PV or one of Umongous' related websites. You may opt-out from receiving these emails by selecting the opt-out link in the email. We will never send you a promotional email related to a product or service that is not part of the Umongous business and related websites. 

## How We Notify You About Changes to Our Privacy Policy

If we decide to change our privacy policy, we will post those changes to this privacy statement, the home page, and other places we deem appropriate, so that you are aware of what information we collect, how we use it, and under what circumstances, if any, we disclose it. 

We reserve the right to modify this privacy statement at any time, so please review it frequently. If we make material changes to this policy, we will notify you here, by email, or by means of a notice on our home page prior to the change becoming effective. 

If your personal information changes, or if you no longer desire our service, you may correct, update, amend, delete/remove by making the change on our member information page or by contacting us at the contact information below. We will respond to your request to access within 30 days. 

## Data Retention

We will retain your information for as long as your account is active, or as needed, to provide you services. If you wish to cancel your account or request that we no longer use your information to provide you services, please contact support [at] paidviewpoint [dot] com. We will retain and use your information as necessary to comply with our legal obligations, to resolve disputes, enforce our agreements and TOS. 

## How to Contact Us About Your Privacy Concerns

PV can be reached at any time by email at privacy [at] paidviewpoint [dot] com. It is our practice to respond to emails in less than 48 hours. If we do not respond within 48 hours, call us at (650) 353-7862 and leave a message including your email address so we can respond via email. We will respond to your voicemail within one business day. You can also write us at: Umongous, Inc 123 10th St. San Francisco, CA 94103
